jobcredits.com 2017-07-25

# Privacy Policy | First Advantage

## FIRST ADVANTAGE® CORPORATION   
PRIVACY POLICY 

Our Privacy Policy comprises a number of components. Click any link below to be transferred to the appropriate section: 

  * Privacy Policy for all countries except those below
  * Privacy Policy for use of the First Advantage® web site
  * European Union Privacy Shield Privacy Policy
  * Switzerland Privacy Shield Privacy Policy
  * Privacy Policy for Australia and New Zealand
  * Privacy Policy for Japan
  * Data Protection Contact for Canada
  * Data Protection Contact for Singapore
  * Grievance Officer for India

### PRIVACY POLICY FOR ALL COUNTRIES EXCEPT THOSE SET FORTH BELOW 

**First Advantage® Privacy Vision   **

First Advantage® is committed to the responsible use of information and protecting individual privacy rights.  First Advantage® strives to provide services to businesses, consumers, non-profit organizations and government agencies that help reduce fraud, mitigate risk, facilitate more informed decisions, and make society safer, in ways that protect consumer privacy.  We aspire to protect consumer privacy through the design of our products, by credentialing, monitoring, and auditing our customers as appropriate, and through other information security safeguards.  We also strive to promote transparency through consumer education initiatives, privacy principles and policies, and appropriate opportunities for consumer choice, access, and correction with respect to personal information about the consumer. 

**Data Privacy Principles  **

The First Advantage® Data Privacy Principles speak to the personally identifiable information including sensitive personally identifiable information, collected, maintained, used or disseminated in connection with services offered by First Advantage®, or by its affiliates (all hereinafter "First Advantage®"). 

First Advantage® applies these Principles to our domestic U.S. products and services where appropriate.  In addition, other uses or disclosures may occur as required by applicable law, such as the Fair Credit Reporting Act and its state analogues ("FCRA"), the Driver's Privacy Protection Act and its state analogues ("DPPA"), and the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act ("GLB").  If the law requires or upon request of law enforcement, or, if necessary, to prevent fraud or to protect our computer systems, these principles may not apply. First Advantage® also, from time to time, may revise our Data Privacy Principles by posting changes on its Web site. 

**1\. SECURITY  **

Data security is a company imperative.  First Advantage® strives to protect personally identifiable information that we maintain or disseminate, including through the use of appropriate administrative, physical, and technical safeguards, so it is not obtained by unauthorized individuals or used impermissibly. 

**2.   DISTRIBUTION OF PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION **

First Advantage® seeks to limit the distribution of personally identifiable information consistent with the nature and sensitivity of the information. In its services, First Advantage® also strives to make available personally identifiable information from sources other than public records or publicly available information only to its authorized users or customers. Similarly, where applicable, First Advantage® strives to restrict access to information in accordance with privacy laws such as the FCRA, the GLB, and the DPPA and comparable state statutes. In the case of public record information available to the general public (such as bankruptcy, liens, judgments, criminal records and Uniform Commercial Code filings) and publicly available information (such as telephone directory information or personal information available through widely available media), we may make this information available to the general public unless applicable law operates to limit our distribution of such information to authorized users. 

If, upon investigation, First Advantage® finds that personally identifiable information has been used or accessed inappropriately or unlawfully, First Advantage® strives to take reasonable steps to stop the misuse or access, educate the user concerning the appropriate use of the information, and prevent similar future misuses. Such steps may include measures up to and including discontinuation of the user's access to First Advantage® information products and services, pursuit of other legal remedies, and the referral of misuse to the appropriate authorities. 

**3\. ACCURACY  **

First Advantage® strives to accurately report information in its products. First Advantage® also strives to accurately report information that it receives from its data sources. First Advantage® recognizes, however, that reporting errors may occur and offers consumers opportunities, where applicable, to dispute and correct information that we report as discussed further in Principle 9 on Access and Correction. 

**4\. PROTECTION OF SOCIAL SECURITY NUMBERS AND DRIVER'S LICENSE NUMBERS  **

First Advantage® strives to provide additional safeguards for sensitive personally identifiable information, such as Social Security numbers and driver's license numbers. First Advantage® strives to limit the availability and access to full Social Security Numbers ("SSNs"), Driver's License Numbers and State Identification Numbers. First Advantage® strives to protect the confidentiality of SSNs by limiting access to SSNs to certain legitimate and authorized users, such as: state, local and federal government entities; financial institutions; insurers; employers; creditors; debt collectors and other user types to which First Advantage® may decide to provide such access. A limited number of public records may contain SSNs that are already available to the public and, if such public records are accessed through First Advantage® services, our services may provide access to such SSNs. First Advantage® prohibits the unlawful disclosure of SSNs. First Advantage® also takes steps to limit the availability of Driver's License Numbers ("DLNs") and state identification card numbers.  

**5.   EDUCATION **

First Advantage® strives to inform its employees, users and the general public about appropriate use of First Advantage® products and services.  First Advantage® strives to inform its users and employees about: 

-    Privacy and security issues associated with First Advantage® information products and services; and   
-    The responsible use of personally identifiable information. 

First Advantage® strives to inform the public about: 

\-    The responsible use of personally identifiable information; and   
\-    Measures First Advantage® has undertaken to enhance consumer privacy; and choices available to consumers regarding information access and the ability to opt-out of certain products and services which utilize personally identifiable information. 

**6.   REPUTABLE SOURCES **

First Advantage® strives to acquire personally identifiable information from established, reputable sources in the government and private sectors. In support of this Principle, First Advantage® takes reasonable steps to assess the reputation and reliability of its private sector data sources before incorporating personally identifiable information from the source into its products and services. First Advantage® also strives to obtain assurances from its data suppliers that they have the legal right to license or sell the data to First Advantage®. 

**7\. NOTICE  **

First Advantage® strives to make its Data Privacy Principles publicly known. First Advantage® publicly posts these Data Privacy Principles. 

Security;  

Distribution of Personally Identifiable Information;  

Accuracy; 

Protection of Social Security Numbers and Driver's License Numbers; 

Education; 

Reputable Sources; 

Notice; 

Choice; 

Access and Correction; 

Accountability; 

Online Privacy; 

Identity Theft; and 

Compliance 

**8\. CHOICE  **

First Advantage® strives to allow consumers to opt-out of the dissemination of personally identifiable information from certain First Advantage® owned databases used solely for marketing services. 

**9\. ACCESS & CORRECTION **

First Advantage® strives to provide consumers with a central point of contact regarding their questions about First Advantage® and its commitment to the responsible use of personally identifiable information. First Advantage® strives to inform individuals about the nature of the public records, non-public information, and publicly available information that First Advantage® makes available in its information products and services. First Advantage® also strives, whenever practicable, to provide consumers, upon request, with meaningful opportunities to review personally identifiable information we maintain about them. First Advantage® also strives, as appropriate and practicable, to provide opportunities for consumers to dispute and correct information by assisting them in identifying the potential information sources at which corrections should be made. First Advantage® strives to direct individuals to the government and private entities that collect and maintain public records and publicly available information to correct any claimed inaccuracies found in that data, and to direct individuals to consumer reporting agencies where such agency is the source of the information about the individual and where the individual seeks to correct claimed inaccuracies found in that data. 

**10\. ACCOUNTABILITY  **

First Advantage® supports accountability of information industry standards and practices, responsible and effective federal regulation of the data industry, and legislation governing the practices of all data providers. First Advantage® also supports industry oversight and active engagement with the privacy community. First Advantage® believes that strong privacy and information security protections are vital for an effective and trusted data industry. 

**11\. ONLINE PRIVACY  **

First Advantage® strives to protect the privacy of personally identifiable information obtained over the Internet and strives to apply our Data Privacy Principles and evolving standards to the online environment. 

**12\. IDENTITY THEFT  **

First Advantage® strives to prevent the acquisition of information from its products and services for improper purposes, such as identity theft. First Advantage® believes that it is important that individuals who may have had their sensitive personally identifiable information acquired by an unauthorized individual be notified as follows: Where a state law requires notice, First Advantage® complies with the law. In those states where notification laws do not exist, First Advantage® follows its Information Security Breach Response and Notification Policy, which provides that affected individuals will be notified when sensitive personally identifiable information owned or licensed by First Advantage® is acquired by an unauthorized individual and whenever First Advantage® has a reasonable basis to believe the breach has resulted in, or there is a significant risk that it will result in, identity theft to the consumer to whom the information relates. 

**13\. COMPLIANCE  **

First Advantage® will obtain assessments from a qualified, objective, independent third-party, who uses procedures and standards generally accepted in the profession to assess First Advantage®' administrative, technical, and physical safeguards, as appropriate. 

**How We Use and Collect Information in Our Various Businesses   ** 

A number of First Advantage® businesses are consumer reporting agencies (CRAs) operating in accordance with the requirements of the Fair Credit Reporting Act (FCRA). FCRA establishes the following principles for all CRAs: 

Privacy: Information about you may only be furnished to third parties that have a permissible purpose. In general, these deal with credit, employment, insurance, rental or banking transactions initiated by you, or where the object is to make a firm offer to you. CRAs must qualify their customers to make certain that they have a permissible purpose to receive the information. 

Access: Consumers may receive a copy of information the CRA maintains about them. Such reports can be obtained free of charge once per year or for a reasonable fee for additional disclosures. Please visit the applicable subsidiary Web sites to obtain more information. 

Accuracy: CRAs must follow reasonable procedures to assure accuracy of the information they maintain and furnish. When you obtain a copy of your information, you have a right to dispute and have the information reinvestigated and corrected in the CRAs database. 

Fairness: Information is obtained from various sources including public records sources. However, certain information over a specified time period may not be reported. 

Accountability: The Federal Trade Commission is charged with overseeing the operations of CRAs and enforcing FCRA requirements. 

First Advantage® companies subject to FCRA operate within this framework. If you would like to obtain a report about the information we have about you, please call 800-845-6004 or go to [http://www.fadv.com/](http://www.fadv.com/free-report-for-consumers.aspx)[fcra.aspx](http://www.fadv.com/fcra.aspx).

For credit reports from the credit bureaus:    

**Privacy Notice: Preparation and Processing of Investigative Consumer Reports   ** 

This notice is provided to California residents. Under California law, an "investigative consumer report" is a consumer report containing information on a consumer's character, general reputation, personal characteristics, or mode of living. First Advantage® compiles investigative consumer reports about individuals and provides them to business for background screening, tenant screening, and similar purposes.   

Personal Information Disclosure: United States or Overseas – In connection with its preparation and processing of investigative consumer reports, First Advantage® may transfer personal information about you to our authorized service providers and affiliates outside the United States and its territories. Such transfer will be conducted in accordance with all applicable laws and regulations.  

To obtain additional information about the privacy practices and policies of First Advantage® in connection with its preparation and processing of investigative consumer reports, please contact:  

First Advantage® Corporation   
Bret Jardine, Esq.   
General Counsel   
United States   
Telephone: +1.678.710.7260   
Email: [privacy@fadv.com](mailto:privacy@fadv.com)   

For additional information about privacy or consumer reporting, visit the following Web sites:  

Federal Trade Commission: [www.ftc.gov](http://www.ftc.gov/)[ ](http://www.ftc.gov/)   
Consumer Financial Protection Bureau: [http://www.consumerfinance.gov/](http://www.cdiaonline.org/)   
Consumer Data Industry Association: [www.cdiaonline.org](http://www.cdiaonline.org/)    
Experian: [www.experian.com/](http://www.experian.com/consumer/credit_education.html)   
Equifax: [https://www.econsumer.equifax.com/](https://www.econsumer.equifax.com/consumer/landing.ehtml?^start=&companyName=PSHP1_hpg)   
TransUnion: [https://www.transunion.com/](https://www.transunion.com/customer-support/contact-us#)   
California Office of Privacy Protection: [www.privacy.ca.gov](http://www.privacy.ca.gov/)   

All other requests, including customer and job applicant, help, support or additional information please visit our contact page or call: 

U.S. client support: 800.888.5773   
APAC client support: +65 6534 3262   
Canadian client support: 1.800.833.7511   
EMEA client support: +44 (0) 8448 24 34 44 

**PRIVACY POLICY FOR USE OF THE FIRST ADVANTAGE® WEB SITE  **

Welcome to First Advantage®'s Web site. Please carefully read our privacy policy to understand how we will treat the information you provide while visiting this Web site ("Web site"). This policy may change from time to time. Please check the policy each time you use our Web site for the most current information. This policy only applies to this First Advantage® Web site accessing through www.fadv.com; some of First Advantage®'s subsidiaries and affiliates may maintain their own privacy policies. Please refer to those Web sites for further information. This Web site is not intended for children and we do not knowingly collect any information about children.   

We also apply this privacy policy in the offline context in those limited cases where we require a consumer to provide his or her Social Security Number in order for the consumer to order an information product by mail or telephone. 

First Advantage® is a leading provider of risk mitigation and business solutions. We offer clients a comprehensive portfolio of best-in-class products, services and innovative tools to help them make smarter business decisions and empower them with timely, quality information. In order to market our services effectively and with due regard for the interests of consumers, we recognize that we have an obligation to protect the privacy and confidentiality of personally identifiable information (PII) that we may obtain about individuals through this Web site. Safeguarding the privacy of information we receive on this Web site is a top priority for consumers, our customers and First Advantage®. 

**How We Collect and Use Information on Our Web Site   **

We follow the below privacy principles when you visit this Web site. In general, you can visit this First Advantage® Web site on the World Wide Web without telling us who you are or revealing any information about yourself. Our Web servers automatically collect the domain names, not the e-mail addresses, of visitors. This information is used to measure the number of visits, average time spent on the site, pages viewed and similar information. First Advantage® uses this information to measure the use of our Web site and to develop ideas to improve the content of our Web site.   

**I. Personally-identifiable information**  

This site only collects personally-identifiable information from you if you choose to provide this information to us. Personally-identifiable information collected with your consent may include name, mailing address, e-mail address, telephone number, date of birth, credit card number, social security number, driver's license number, user name and password, any response you provide to survey questions, information relating to any orders you place, or any inquires you may make through our web site. We also may request this type of information if you place an order by mail or telephone. 

**II. Cookies  **

"Cookies" are small pieces of information that are stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive. This site uses first and third party cookies, however personally identifiable information is not collected through the use of cookies. Cookies allow us to store your User ID during your visit to keep track of reports you have ordered or any updates to those reports. Cookies also help us detect potential fraud or misuse of our system. 

While most browsers are set to accept cookies by default, you can set yours to refuse cookies or to alert you before accepting them. Your browser manufacturer has information on changing the default setting for your specific browser. However, be aware that if you do not accept cookies from this web site, you will not be able to use some of the features of this site, such as those for ordering reports.   

**III. Non-personally-identifiable information**  

This site also collects non-personally-identifiable information. For example, as you browse this web site we may collect information about your visit, but not about you personally. Via web server logs, for example, we may monitor statistics such as: the number of people that visit our site, which page(s) are visited on our site, from which domain our visitors come (e.g., aol.com, hotmail.com, etc.), and which browsers people use to visit our site (e.g., Google Chrome, Microsoft Internet Explorer, etc.). Our web site may use an outsourcing program to assist us in analyzing this data to better tailor our web site. 

**POLICY CHANGES  ** 

We may revise this online privacy policy from time to time. If we make any material changes, we will notify you by posting a prominent announcement on the web site. If we are going to use your personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection we will notify you via email if an email address has been provided and is available. You will have a choice as to whether or not we use your information in this different manner. 

**INFORMATION USE AND CONSUMER CHOICE   **

The information collected by this web site is used only for responding to your inquiries and otherwise corresponding with you, for processing transactions you request, maintaining your account (if you have one), and for the administration, review and/or the improvement the content of our web sites. We do not share, sell, rent or trade PII with third parties for their promotional purposes. 

We may contact you in response to your comments or inquiries, as part of the maintenance of your account with us (if you have one), or in order to complete a transaction that you requested. 

We may also contact you to inform you of other products or services we think may be of interest to you, but we always offer you an opportunity to opt not to receive such communications. 

If you decide that you do not want to receive further e-mails regarding your inquiry from First Advantage®, you can reply to the e-mail we sent or send an email to [firstadvantage@learn.fadv.com](mailto:firstadvantage@learn.fadv.com) with a request that we not continue to e-mail you. We do not use outside data sources to enrich marketing data obtained online. 

**ONWARD TRANSFER   **

We may disclose information you provide to us to third parties in order to complete a transaction that you requested. If, for example, you pay for a transaction using a credit card, disclosing that information for processing purposes is necessary to complete the transaction. In other cases, it may be necessary to disclose information you provide about yourself or third parties in order to obtain the information product you requested. We may also outsource some tasks, including the operation of some website functions, which require access to information you supply online. In such cases, however, we require that the companies acting on our behalf abide by our privacy policy and institute safeguards to protect the confidentiality of your information. 

If our company or our assets are acquired by another company, that company will assume responsibility for the personal information collected by us through this Web site and it will assume the rights and obligations regarding the information collected through this Web site, as described in this privacy policy. 

Finally, please note that we may disclose personal information when required by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary in order to conform to the law or to comply with a legal process. 

**ACCESS AND CORRECTION  ** 

As an information company, we know the importance of accurate data. Therefore, we strive to maintain the accuracy of the information collected through this Web site. We will provide you (whether you are a consumer or a customer) with access to personally-identifiable information you provide through this Web site for as long as we maintain that information in a readily accessible format. Similarly, we permit and encourage you to correct inaccuracies in the information you submit to us through this Web site. 

If you wish to access information that you have submitted through this web site or to request the correction of any inaccurate information you have submitted through this site, please use the mechanisms provided by the site, or send an e-mail to [privacy@fadv.com](mailto:privacy@fadv.com). 

The access and correction provisions of this online privacy policy only apply to personally identifiable information collected from you through this web site. Individuals that are interested in information about how to access and/or request the correction of personal information First Advantage® companies maintain about them for potential inclusion in information products and services can contact [privacy@fadv.com](mailto:privacy@fadv.com). 

**SECURITY  ** 

We take steps to protect against the loss, misuse, or unauthorized alteration of personally-identifiable information collected through this web site and otherwise subject to this policy. We recognize the importance of security for all personally-identifiable information collected by our web site. Once we receive personally-identifiable information, we take steps to protect its security on our systems. In the event we request or transmit sensitive information, such as credit card information or Social Security Numbers through this web site, we use industry standard, secure socket layer (SSL) encryption. 

We limit access to personally-identifiable information to those employees who need access in order to carry out their job responsibilities. 

When we dispose of personally identifiable information collected through this website, we use procedures to dispose of personal information by means such as shredding documents and erasure of electronic media that information cannot be practicably read or reconstructed. 

**OTHER WEB SITES  ** 

In the online context, this online privacy policy only applies to the Web site(s) identified in the first paragraph of this privacy policy. Our Web site, however, may include links to other Web sites which may be operated by other First Advantage® companies or by third parties. If you visit a Web site not listed above, we recommend that you review the online privacy policy of that Web site to determine how the operator of that Web site will handle personal information collected through that Web site. 

**EUROPEAN UNION PRIVACY SHIELD PRIVACY POLICY  **

First Advantage Corporation and its U.S. subsidiaries (“First Advantage”) have committed to handling EU Personal Data received in accordance with the EU-US Privacy Shield Principles set forth in the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework administered by the Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use and retention of EU Personal Data. “EU Personal Data” is data pertaining to an identified or identifiable individual that is received by First Advantage from the European Union (including Iceland, Norway and Liechtenstein).

  First Advantage has certified that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles of Notice, Choice, Accountability for Onward Transfer, Security, Data Integrity and Purpose Limitation, Access, and Recourse, Enforcement and Liability. Our Privacy Shield certification can be found at [www.privacyshield.gov/list](http://www.privacyshield.gov/list).

  In compliance with the EU-US Privacy Shield Principles, First Advantage commits to resolve complaints about our collection or use of your personal information. Individuals in the European Union with inquiries or complaints regarding this policy should first contact First Advantage at [privacy@fadv.com](mailto:privacy@fadv.com) or at one of the contacts provided below. If such a complaint goes unresolved, First Advantage further commits to comply with the advice of a panel of EU Data Protection Authorities established to investigate and resolve Privacy Shield complaints (“EU DPA Panel”). Contact details for the EU data protection authorities can be found at [http://ec.europa.eu/](http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/bodies/authorities/index_en.htm). Finally, First Advantage agrees to participate in binding arbitration for any complaints unresolved by the EU DPA Panel that meet the conditions set forth in Annex I of the Privacy Shield requirements. For more information about binding arbitration please visit:  [www.privacyshield.gov](http://www.privacyshield.gov/). All of the above described recourse mechanisms are available at no cost to you.

  In cases where First Advantage transfers EU Personal Data received pursuant to the EU-US Privacy Shield onward to third party agents, First Advantage is potentially liable under the Privacy Shield Principles if its agents process that EU Personal Data in a manner inconsistent with the Principles, unless First Advantage is not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage. In the event of a conflict between this policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern.

  First Advantage is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission. First Advantage may be required to disclose personal information in response to a lawful request by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

**1\. Notice  **

First Advantage receives certain EU Personal Data at the request of clients and other third parties for investigative, credential verification, and employment related purposes, as well as credit and fraud risk mitigation related purposes.   

  Where permissible, First Advantage gathers and maintains consumer and other data which it provides to its clients (employers or their agents, such as recruiters or staffing firms) for use in making employment-related decisions, such as who to hire, retain, promote, or re-assign. First Advantage also gathers and maintains consumer and other data which it provides to entities including lenders, credit reference agencies and fraud prevention agencies. Provided below is an illustrative list of common ways in which employers use the data provided by this service: 

  * Performance of applicant and employee background checks  
  * Verification of the credentials of job applicants and current employees  
  * Investigation into a suspicion of work-related misconduct or wrongdoing  
  * Investigation into matters of employee compliance with employer policies, or  
  * Investigation into matters of employee compliance with Federal, State, or local laws and regulations  

Provided below is an illustrative list of common ways in which lenders, credit reference agencies and fraud prevention agencies use the data provided by this service (where available): 

  * Authentication of consumer applicants for loans or other credit services 
  * Prevention or detection of fraud by consumer applicants for loans or other credit services 
  * Determination of credit worthiness or capacity of consumer applicants for loans or other credit services 
  * Location of absconded borrowers 

First Advantage uses a limited number of third party service providers to assist us in providing our services to customers. These third party providers perform reference and credential verifications and complete portions of services requested by our customers, such as by obtaining records from data sources. These third parties may access or process personal data in the course of providing their services. First Advantage maintains contracts with these third parties restricting their access, use and disclosure of personal data in compliance with our Privacy Shield obligations.

  The scope of this notice also covers consumer report data that First Advantage has obtained on behalf of employers and other businesses by manually or electronically contacting the appropriate sources of the data (court records, education and employment references, licensing bureaus, etc.). First Advantage also performs services related to corporate litigation and investigative services as requested by our clients.  

  More information regarding the nature and scope of consumer data inquiries is available by contacting First Advantage in writing or by e-mail at the addresses listed on the [Contact Us page](https://www.fadv.com/contact-us.aspx) or by writing to the contacts listed below.

**2\. Choice   **

First Advantage or its clients will offer individuals the opportunity to choose (opt-out) whether their EU Personal Data will be disclosed to a third party (not including our agents) or will be used for a purpose other than the purpose for which it was originally collected or subsequently authorized by the individual. With respect to sensitive information, however, an individual must "opt-in" to the disclosure of the information to a non-agent third party or to the use of this information for a purpose other than its original purpose or that purpose authorized subsequently by the individual. First Advantage or its clients will provide individuals with a readily-available mechanism to exercise their choices should circumstances arise that require opt-out or opt-in. In addition, First Advantage will treat as sensitive any EU Personal Data received from a third party where the third party identifies and treats it as sensitive.

**3\. Onward Transfer (Transfers to Third Parties)   **

With respect to the transfer of EU Personal Data to third parties (other than our agents), the principles of "Notice" and "Choice" apply. Accordingly, EU Personal Data is only provided to these types of third parties for purposes described in the "Notice" section or otherwise disclosed to consumers, and will not be disseminated to such a third party where a consumer has "opted-out" or, in the case of sensitive information, failed to "opt-in."  

  Non-agent third parties to whom we transfer EU Personal Data will be obligated to provide the same level of protection as the Privacy Shield Principles.

  First Advantage may disclose EU Personal Data to clients and third parties acting as agents. We will transfer such data only for limited and specified purposes and ascertain that agents are obligated to provide at least the same level of privacy protection as is required by the Privacy Shield Principles.

**4\. Security  ** 

First Advantage takes reasonable and appropriate measures to protect EU Personal Data from loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction.   

**5\. Data Integrity and Purpose Limitation  **

First Advantage collects EU Personal Data that is relevant for the purpose(s) for which it is to be used, consistent with the Privacy Shield Principles.  We process EU Personal Data in ways that are compatible with the purpose(s) for which it has been collected (as identified in the Notice section above, or as subsequently authorized by the individual).  To the extent necessary for those purposes, First Advantage takes reasonable steps to ensure that EU Personal Data collected is accurate, complete, current, and reliable for its intended use. First Advantage retains EU Personal Data only for as long as it serves a purpose of processing.

**6\. Access   **

A consumer may request, in writing, access to EU Personal Data collected and maintained about him or her, which First Advantage will make a good faith effort to provide. First Advantage affords the consumer a reasonable opportunity to correct, amend, or delete information that is inaccurate or incomplete, except where the burden or expense of providing access would be disproportionate to the risks to the individual's privacy, or where the rights of persons other than the individual would be violated. 

  First Advantage reserves the right to engage in reasonable efforts to confirm the identity of the individual requesting EU Personal Data to ensure the information is provided only to the subject of the data.    
To request information relating to his or her EU Personal Data, a consumer may contact First Advantage in writing or by e-mail at the following email address: privacy@fadv.com; or by writing to the contacts listed below. In addition, the consumer will be asked to provide sufficient evidence of his or her identity so we may ensure that information is being released to the correct individual. If we are unable to provide the consumer with access to his or her EU Personal Data or to correct the data, we will notify the consumer.

**7\. Recourse, Enforcement and Liability  **

First Advantage will verify that its attestations and assertions about its privacy practices with respect to Privacy Shield are true and that those privacy practices have been implemented as presented via in-house verification and internal policies and procedures implemented by First Advantage management. First Advantage will take reasonable and appropriate steps to remediate any issue that comes to its attention with respect to compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles.

  As described above, First Advantage will cooperate with the EU DPA Panel as an independent, readily available recourse mechanism by which individual consumer complaints and disputes that cannot be resolved between the consumer and First Advantage can be investigated and remedied at no cost to the individual and by reference to the Privacy Shield Principles.   

  First Advantage will respond promptly to inquiries and requests by the Department of Commerce for information related to the Privacy Shield, as well as to complaints regarding compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles referred by the EU Data Protection Authorities through the Department of Commerce.

  First Advantage will arbitrate claims and follow the terms set forth in Annex I of the Privacy Shield requirements, provided that an individual has properly invoked binding arbitration and delivered notice to First Advantage in accordance with the appropriate procedures and conditions.

**8\. Amendments  ** 

From time to time, this policy may be amended to reflect new products and services, or as necessary to reflect a new business practice.  Consistent with the Privacy Shield requirements, we will post any revised policy on this website.   

**CONTACT INFORMATION  ** 

To request information relating to your EU Personal Data, please contact: [privacy@fadv.com](mailto:privacy@fadv.com). 

If you have questions regarding this European Union Privacy Shield Privacy Policy, contact:   

   First Advantage® Corporation   
   Angeli C. Heyne, Esq.   
   Senior Attorney, Regional Compliance Officer EMEA & Dubai  
   100 Carillon Parkway, Suite 350  
   St. Petersburg, FL 33716   
   United States   
Telephone: +1.813.682.3664   
Email: [privacy@fadv.com](mailto:privacy@fadv.com)

**Switzerland Privacy Shield Privacy Policy**  

First Advantage Corporation and its U.S. subsidiaries (“First Advantage”) complies with the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the Switzerland to the United States.  First Advantage has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles.  If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern.  To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>.

  “Swiss Personal Data” is data pertaining to an identified or identifiable individual that is received by First Advantage from Switzerland.

  In compliance with the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Principles, First Advantage commits to resolve complaints about our collection or use of your personal information. Individuals in Switzerland with inquiries or complaints regarding this policy should first contact First Advantage at [privacy@fadv.com](mailto:privacy@fadv.com) or at one of the contacts provided below. If such a complaint goes unresolved, First Advantage further commits to comply with the advice of the Swiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner’s authority established to investigate and resolve Privacy Shield complaints (“FDPIC”). Contact details for the FDPIC can be found at [https://www.edoeb.admin.ch](https://www.edoeb.admin.ch/org/00926/index.html?lang=en). All of the above described recourse mechanisms are available at no cost to you.

  In cases where First Advantage transfers Swiss Personal Data received pursuant to the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield onward to third party agents, First Advantage is potentially liable under the Privacy Shield Principles if its agents process that Swiss Personal Data in a manner inconsistent with the Principles, unless First Advantage is not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage. In the event of a conflict between this policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern.

  First Advantage is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission. First Advantage may be required to disclose personal information in response to a lawful request by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

**1\. Notice    **

First Advantage receives certain Swiss Personal Data at the request of customers and other third parties for investigative, credential verification, and employment related purposes, as well as credit and fraud risk mitigation related purposes.   

  Where permissible, First Advantage gathers and maintains consumer and other data which it provides to its clients (employers or their agents, such as recruiters or staffing firms) for use in making employment-related decisions, such as who to hire, retain, promote, or re-assign. First Advantage also gathers and maintains consumer and other data which it provides to entities including lenders, credit reference agencies and fraud prevention agencies. Provided below is an illustrative list of common ways in which employers use the data provided by this service: 

  * Performance of applicant and employee background checks  
  * Verification of the credentials of job applicants and current employees  
  * Investigation into a suspicion of work-related misconduct or wrongdoing  
  * Investigation into matters of employee compliance with employer policies, or  
  * Investigation into matters of employee compliance with Federal, State, or local laws and regulations  

Provided below is an illustrative list of common ways in which lenders, credit reference agencies and fraud prevention agencies use the data provided by this service (where available): 

  * Authentication of consumer applicants for loans or other credit services 
  * Prevention or detection of fraud by consumer applicants for loans or other credit services 
  * Determination of credit worthiness or capacity of consumer applicants for loans or other credit services 
  * Location of absconded borrowers 

First Advantage uses a limited number of third party service providers to assist us in providing our services to customers. These third party providers perform reference and credential verifications and complete portions of services requested by our customers, such as by obtaining records from data sources. These third parties may access or process personal data in the course of providing their services. First Advantage maintains contracts with these third parties restricting their access, use and disclosure of personal data in compliance with our Privacy Shield obligations.

  The scope of this notice also covers consumer report data that First Advantage has obtained on behalf of employers and other businesses by manually or electronically contacting the appropriate sources of the data (court records, education and employment references, licensing bureaus, etc.). First Advantage also performs services related to corporate litigation and investigative services as requested by our clients.  

  More information regarding the nature and scope of consumer data inquiries is available by contacting First Advantage in writing or by e-mail at the addresses listed on the [Contact Us page](https://www.fadv.com/contact-us.aspx) or by writing to the contacts listed below.  

**2\. Choice  ** 

First Advantage or its clients will offer individuals the opportunity to choose (opt-out) whether their Swiss Personal Data will be disclosed to a third party (not including our agents) or will be used for a purpose other than the purpose for which it was originally collected or subsequently authorized by the individual. With respect to sensitive information, however, an individual must "opt-in" to the disclosure of the information to a non-agent third party or to the use of this information for a purpose other than its original purpose or that purpose authorized subsequently by the individual. First Advantage or its customers will provide individuals with a readily-available mechanism to exercise their choices should circumstances arise that require opt-out or opt-in. In addition, First Advantage will treat as sensitive any Swiss Personal Data received from a third party where the third party identifies and treats it as sensitive.

**3\. Onward Transfer (Transfers to Third Parties)  ** 

With respect to the transfer of Swiss Personal Data to third parties (other than our agents), the principles of "Notice" and "Choice" apply. Accordingly, Swiss Personal Data is only provided to these types of third parties for purposes described in the "Notice" section or otherwise disclosed to consumers, and will not be disseminated to such a third party where a consumer has "opted-out" or, in the case of sensitive information, failed to "opt-in."  

  Non-agent third parties to whom we transfer Swiss Personal Data will be obligated to provide the same level of protection as the Privacy Shield Principles.

  First Advantage may disclose Swiss Personal Data to clients and third parties acting as agents. We will transfer such data only for limited and specified purposes and ascertain that agents are obligated to provide at least the same level of privacy protection as is required by the Privacy Shield Principles.

**4\. Security   **

First Advantage takes reasonable and appropriate measures to protect Swiss Personal Data from loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction.  

**5\. Data Integrity and Purpose Limitation   **

First Advantage collects Swiss Personal Data that is relevant for the purpose(s) for which it is to be used, consistent with the Privacy Shield Principles.  We process Swiss Personal Data in ways that are compatible with the purpose(s) for which it has been collected (as identified in the Notice section above, or as subsequently authorized by the individual).  To the extent necessary for those purposes, First Advantage takes reasonable steps to ensure that Swiss Personal Data collected is accurate, complete, current, and reliable for its intended use. First Advantage retains Swiss Personal Data only for as long as it serves a purpose of processing.   

**6\. Access  **

A consumer may request, in writing, access to Swiss Personal Data collected and maintained about him or her, which First Advantage will make a good faith effort to provide. First Advantage affords the consumer a reasonable opportunity to correct, amend, or delete information that is inaccurate or incomplete, except where the burden or expense of providing access would be disproportionate to the risks to the individual's privacy, or where the rights of persons other than the individual would be violated. 

  First Advantage reserves the right to engage in reasonable efforts to confirm the identity of the individual requesting Swiss Personal Data to ensure the information is provided only to the subject of the data.  

  To request information relating to his or her Swiss Personal Data, a consumer may contact First Advantage in writing or by e-mail at the following email address: privacy@fadv.com; or by writing to the contacts listed below. In addition, the consumer will be asked to provide sufficient evidence of his or her identity so we may ensure that information is being released to the correct individual. If we are unable to provide the consumer with access to his or her Swiss Personal Data or to correct the data, we will notify the consumer. 

**7\. Recourse, Enforcement and Liability**

First Advantage will verify that its attestations and assertions about its privacy practices with respect to Privacy Shield are true and that those privacy practices have been implemented as presented via in-house verification and internal policies and procedures implemented by First Advantage management. First Advantage will take reasonable and appropriate steps to remediate any issue that comes to its attention with respect to compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles.

  As described above, First Advantage will cooperate with the FDPIC as an independent, readily available recourse mechanism by which individual consumer complaints and disputes that cannot be resolved between the consumer and First Advantage can be investigated and remedied at no cost to the individual and by reference to the Privacy Shield Principles.   

  First Advantage will respond promptly to inquiries and requests by the Department of Commerce for information related to the Privacy Shield, as well as to complaints regarding compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles referred by the FDPIC through the Department of Commerce.

**8\. Amendments**   

From time to time, this policy may be amended to reflect new products and services, or as necessary to reflect a new business practice.  Consistent with the Privacy Shield requirements, we will post any revised policy on this website. 

**CONTACT INFORMATION**   

To request information relating to your Switzerland Personal Data, please contact:    

If you have questions regarding our Switzerland Privacy Shield Privacy Policy contact:   

   First Advantage® Corporation   
   Angeli C. Heyne, Esq.   
   Senior Attorney, Regional Compliance Officer EMEA & Dubai  
   100 Carillon Parkway, Suite 350   
   St. Petersburg, FL 33716   
   United States   
Telephone: +1.813.682.3664   
Email: [privacy@fadv.com](mailto:privacy@fadv.com)

**PRIVACY POLICY FOR AUSTRALIA AND NEW ZEALAND  **

**INTRODUCTION  **  
First Advantage® Australia Pty Ltd ABN 67 101 863 209 and First Advantage® New Zealand Limited [NZBN 9429034295540] ("First Advantage®", "we", "us" or "our") provides a background screening service for its clients ("Client"), to assist them in considering individuals for employment, change in the level of responsibility, other circumstances where an individual's background is relevant (including but not limited to insurance and claims review), or to determine if further verification or investigation is necessary.  This is achieved by preparing an employment, investigative, or due diligence report for the Client. 

This policy may change from time to time. Please check the policy each time you use our Web site for the most current information. 

In this Privacy Policy for Australia and New Zealand, the following definitions apply: 

Privacy Legislation means: 

\-    for Australia, the Privacy Act 1988 including the Australian Privacy Principles; and   
\-    for New Zealand, the Privacy Act 1993 including the Information Privacy Principles 

Personal Information has the same meaning as in the Privacy Legislation; ie: 

\-    for Australia, "information or an opinion about an identified individual, or an individual who is reasonably identifiable: (a) whether the information or opinion is true or not; and (b) whether the information or opinion is recorded in a material form or not; and   
\-    for New Zealand, "information about an identifiable individual; and includes information relating to a death that is maintained by the Registrar-General". 

**THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT AND HOLD  **

As part of our services, we receive information about individuals for the purposes of conducting our checks. 

Personal Information that we collect and hold about an individual will vary depending upon the background checks required by the Client and the information the individual supplies to us. Personal Information about an individual that we may collect and hold includes name, age, date of birth, employment history, reference information, education, professional qualifications, residency, sanctions, immigration status, claims, judgments, insolvency, current and previous directorships, character, personal reputation, and such other checks and enquiries as the Client considers necessary to verify information provided by an individual. 

From Clients we may collect company address and the name, email and phone number of any system users. 

From Clients and individuals, we may collect credit card payment details. 

From the sources of our background checks we may collect the name and job title of the person who supplied us with the information. 

We may also collect other Personal Information which is "sensitive information". Sensitive information is given a greater level of protection under the Privacy Legislation. The Privacy Legislation imposes greater obligations on us regarding any collection, use or disclosure we make of an individual's sensitive information. 

Sensitive information about an individual that we may collect and hold includes criminal records, and membership of a professional or trade association. 

We recognise the importance of privacy issues and respect the confidentiality of the Personal Information and sensitive information individuals provide to us. We will collect and deal with Personal Information and sensitive information in accordance with the Privacy Legislation, and our Privacy Statement and this Privacy Policy (all as amended from time to time). 

**MAIN PURPOSES FOR WHICH WE COLLECT, HOLD, USE AND DISCLOSE PERSONAL INFORMATION  **

When engaged by a Client, First Advantage® verifies an individual's information, documentation and any responses by carrying out verification checks for the purposes of preparing an employment, investigative, or due diligence report. This is done at the Client's request to enable them to assess an individual's suitability for employment, promotion, provision of services, or other purposes in accordance with their legal obligations and internal risk management policy (including but not limited to insurance and claims review). 

In certain circumstances, First Advantage® may be engaged by a Client to prepare an employment or investigative report because they are required by law to determine a candidate's suitability for a position of employment. 

**HOW WE COLLECT PERSONAL INFORMATION  **

In order to process and verify information for a Client's request, the Client and First Advantage® may collect an individual's Personal Information directly from the individual. We may also collect information about an individual from a third party a candidate refers us to. In these circumstances, we will assume that the individual has referred First Advantage® to them and informed them of the purposes involved in the collection, use and disclosure of the relevant personal or other information. 

We may use the Personal Information, documentation and any responses an individual or third party reference has provided to us to apply to various other entities ("Sources") for verification of an individual's personal and other information, to collect additional Personal Information, and to conduct public record searches. Examples of Sources include, but are not limited to, government agencies, law enforcement bodies, publicly available records, public registries, court or tribunal records, insolvency registers, educational institutions, current and/or previous employers, and regulatory and licensing bodies. 

**HOW WE HOLD PERSONAL INFORMATION  **

The Personal Information provided to us by an individual, third party references, and any other Personal Information provided by the Sources, will be processed by us. 

First Advantage® will then use the Personal Information to prepare a report outlining the findings of its investigations and provide the report to the Client via a secure means. The Client may then use that information to consider an individual's suitability for employment, change in the level of responsibility, or other circumstances where an individual's background is relevant, or to determine if further verification or investigation is necessary. If a Fit and Proper report was requested, the Client may use this to determine whether an individual meets the requirements as a Fit and Proper Person. If the report was requested for insurance purposes, it may be used by the client to determine eligibility for insurance or for claims payments. 

We store the Personal Information we receive in hard copy files and/or in electronic format in a database. 

We take steps to protect against the loss, misuse, or unauthorized alteration of Personal Information collected and subject to this policy. We recognize the importance of security for all Personal Information collected by First Advantage®. Once we receive Personal Information, we take steps to protect its security on our systems. In the event we request or transmit sensitive information, we use industry standard, secure socket layer (SSL) encryption. 

We limit access to personally-identifiable information to those employees who need this access in order to carry out their job responsibilities. 

When we dispose of personally identifiable information, we use procedures to dispose of Personal Information by means such as shredding documents and erasure of electronic media that information cannot be practicably read or reconstructed. 

We may need to retain Personal Information collected from an individual, third party references, or Sources to comply with our contractual, statutory or other legal obligations even after the employment or other application process is completed or terminated. 

**IDENTIFIERS  **

An "identifier" is a unique identification number assigned to a candidate by the Australian Government or an Australian Government Agency. Examples of identifiers include a Tax File Number (TFN) or a Medicare number. First Advantage® does not use identifiers to identify a candidate's personal information in our systems. 

**OVERSEAS TRANSFERS OF PERSONAL INFORMATION  **

We may disclose Personal Information to overseas recipients. The circumstances of disclosure may be as follows: 

We may need to disclose an individual's Personal Information overseas in order to carry out our checks. For example, if an individual lived, studied or worked overseas, we may need to disclose that individual's Personal Information overseas to liaise with Sources, employers, third party references, or educational institutions. Disclosures of this kind may be to any country in the world, depending upon the circumstances of the individual. 

We may also disclose an individual's Personal Information to our related bodies corporate located overseas, most likely in Australia, India, Canada, New Zealand, the U.S. or the U.K. Personal Information may be disclosed to related bodies corporate located overseas for purposes including data storage, administrative purposes (creating internal and external reports, invoicing and trends in data), and operational and/or processing purposes in connection with the preparation of an employment or investigative report to the Client. 

**ACCESS AND CORRECTION OF INFORMATION**  

An individual has a right to request access to their Personal Information which is held by us. An individual may apply for that information by contacting the Privacy Officer at the contact details set out below. We will acknowledge receipt of a request for access. Where reasonable and practicable, we will provide access to Personal Information in the form requested by an individual. A moderate fee may be charged for this information. Proof of identity may be required. 

We will handle requests for access to Personal Information in accordance with the Privacy Legislation. However, in some circumstances permitted under the Privacy Legislation we may not be required to give an individual access to the information we hold about them. 

It is also important to us that the information we hold about an individual is accurate, complete and up to date. An individual has a right to request the correction of the Personal Information that First Advantage® holds about them. The Individual may do so by lodging a correction request with the Privacy Officer at the contact details listed below. First Advantage® will handle correction requests in accordance with the Privacy Legislation. 

Please note that the Privacy Officer listed below handles requests from Australia and New Zealand.   

**COMPLAINTS  **

If you have a complaint about the way First Advantage® has dealt with your Personal Information, or you would like a copy of the Privacy Policy, please contact our Privacy Officer at: 

   The Privacy Officer   
   First Advantage®   
   PO Box R1783   
   Royal Exchange NSW 1225   
   Australia   
Telephone: +61 2 9017 4300 (AU)   
Telephone: +64 9 438 5232 (NZ)   
Email: [privacy.sapac@fadv.com](mailto:privacy.sapac@fadv.com) 

We will acknowledge receipt of a complaint which we will then endeavour to resolve promptly. The maximum time we will take to investigate the complaint is 30 days. 

If you are not satisfied with the outcome, you may refer the matter to the Privacy Commissioner at: 

For Australia:   
Website: [www.privacy.gov.au](http://www.privacy.gov.au/)   
Email: [enquiries@oaic.gov.au](mailto:enquiries@oaic.gov.au)   
Telephone: 1300 363 992 or +61 2 9284 9749 

For New Zealand:   
Website: [www.privacy.org.au](http://www.privacy.org.au/)   
Email: [enquiries@privacy.org.nz](mailto:enquiries@privacy.org.nz)   
Telephone: 0800 803 909 or +64 4 474 7590 

**PRIVACY POLICY FOR JAPAN  **

Please go to <http://www.fadv.com/japan-privacy.htm>

**DATA PROTECTION CONTACT FOR CANADA  **

Our Data Protection Officer for Canada is Bret Jardine, Esq. 

To request information or receive help with data protection issues, contact our Data Protection Officer at:  

Bret Jardine, Esq.   
Telephone: 800.833.7511 

**DATA PROTECTION CONTACT FOR SINGAPORE  **

Our Data Protection Officer for Singapore is Ian Burnett. 

To request information or receive help with data protection issues, contact our Data Protection Officer at:  

Ian Burnett   
Regional Compliance Officer   
Telephone: +65 6534 3262 or +61 2 9017 4300   
Email: [privacy.sapac@fadv.com](mailto:privacy.sapac@fadv.com) 

**GRIEVANCE OFFICER FOR INDIA  **

As required under The Information Technology Act of India, the name and contact details of the Grievance Officer are as provided below: 

Anselm Pinto   
Regional Compliance Officer    
Telephone: +91 80 3990 9614   
Email: [privacy.napac@fadv.com](mailto:privacy.napac@fadv.com) 

The Grievance Officer is designated exclusively for addressing discrepancies and grievances of data providers with respect to processing of information in a time bound manner. Please do NOT use the contact information for login issues for any portal of First Advantage®.
